The specific harness used at this gym is called the misty mountain jim dandy.
This harness; it's not comfortable, but it does serve purpose.
It'll keep you on the wall.
To put on this harness, you're going to step through the leg loops that are already in place.
Once both legs are through, pull the harness up so it's in line with your waist.
Take the waist belt and wrap that all the way around you, passing it through the buckle next through the blue loop.
Your waist belt should be pretty snug to make sure you don't fall out of it.
Once your waist belt is tightened, you're going to do the final step that's called doubling back.
On this harness, there's a safety feature that engraved danger on the buckle to make sure you know it's not double back.
To make sure you do double your harness back, take the end of the strap, pass it back through the first loop and the buckle you put it through.
Finally, tighten your legs down by pulling the strap through the buckle.
Your leg should be snug but not too tight.
Last step, you have the leg strap here.
This will prevent your leg loops from sliding down and becoming loose.
I tuck that up and over the back of my harness and clip it behind my right leg.
That's how you put on a harness.